原视频名：European Robotic Arm ready for space
原作者名：European Space Agency, ESA
视频来源：youtu.be/dahULS4-rFg
原视频发布日期：20210706
字幕翻译：WJIJKKH，校对：旋火
Soon another piece of cutting-edge European technology will be delivered to the International Space Station.
不久 另一项前沿的欧洲科技将被送往国际空间站
ERA, short for European Robotic Arm
欧洲机械臂 简称为ERA
will be launched on a proton rocket from the Baikonur cosmodrome
将由一枚质子火箭从拜科努尔航天发射场
together with the Russian Multipurpose Laboratory Module, Nauka.
与俄罗斯的多用途实验舱科学号一起发射
This brand-new Russian module will be ERA's home base for the next ten years.
这个全新的俄罗斯舱段将成为ERA未来10年的基地
The 11-metre long ERA-arm can lift up to 8 tons
11米长的ERA臂可以举起8吨重的东西
and be operated with an accuracy of an astonishing 5 millimeters.
并且能以5毫米的惊人精度进行运作
One of the most impressive features of the robotic arm is
该机械臂最令人印象深刻的特点之一是
that it can move hand-over-hand over the Russian module.
它可以在俄罗斯舱段上手拉手似的移动
The ERA-arm is almost completely symmetrical.
ERA臂几乎是完全对称的
西采·坎彭，ERA项目经理，空客国防航天荷兰分公司
This means it has a hand or an end-effector at both sides
这意味着它在两边都有一只手 或着说是都有一个末端执行器
and that each side can serve as the tip as well as the shoulder.
而且每一侧都可以作为末端和肩部摇摆工作
So it means that if you have multiple base points on the on the Russian segment
因此这意味着 如果你在俄罗斯舱段上有多个基点
you can go from one base point to the other
你可以从一个基点移动到另一个基点
then release your shoulder, which becomes tip
然后释放你的肩部摇摆 使其成为末端
and then manipulate a payload.
然后去操纵一个有效载荷
So in that sense, it has freedom of motion on the Space Station.
所以在这个意义上 它可以在空间站上自由移动
With this freedom of motion and well-chosen location
有了这种自由移动的能力和精心选择的基点位置
ERA will be able to service the Russian segment of the Space Station
ERA将能够为空间站的俄罗斯舱段提供服务
which is not in reach of the other two robotic arms already installed.
这是已安装的另外两个机器臂所不能做到的
ERA is fully programmable and has several modes of automation.
ERA是完全可编程的 并且有几种自动化模式
This means each mission can be prepared on the ground
这意味着它的每个任务的程序都可以在地面上进行准备
and then uploaded into the arm's computer
然后上传到机械臂的计算机中
after which the astronauts onboard can run and authorize each step of the mission.
之后 空间站上的宇航员可以运行程序并为每一步任务授权
Theoretically ERA could even work autonomously and run the mission all by itself.
理论上 ERA甚至可以自主工作 并且完全自主地执行任务
It also offers the possibility for astronauts on board
它还为空间站上的宇航员提供了
to piece together a new mission on the fly if necessary.
在有必要时可以在空间站中拼凑出一个新的任务的可能
The arm will have several important applications
该机械臂将有几个重要的应用
to alleviate the work of the astronauts on the International Space Station.
以减轻国际空间站上宇航员的工作
As crew time is precious and the safety of astronauts is paramount
由于空间站成员的时间是宝贵的 而且宇航员的安全是最重要的
the arm can be used for tasks which are described as the three D's
该机械臂可用于被称为三个D的任务
Dull, Dangerous and Difficult.
分别是 无趣的 危险的和困难的
The robotic arm can be used for, for example
该机械臂可用于 例如
安德烈·库佩斯，欧空局宇航员
take payloads out of an airlock autonomously without the risk of an extra vehicular activity
它可以自主地将有效载荷从气闸舱中取出 这避免了舱外活动的风险
for example, and put equipment on the outside.
还有例如 将设备放置在外面
It can be used for inspection.
它可以用于检查
It can be used for putting big new modules, for example
它可以用来放置 例如大的新舱段
and putting it on the Space Station, move big things around.
并把它安装在空间站上 移动大的物体
And also it can be used to help the cosmonauts when they are doing a spacewalk
而且它也可以在宇航员进行太空行走时来帮助他们
to move cosmonauts around or big payloads
来移动宇航员或着大的有效载荷
while the astronauts and cosmonauts have their hands free to work on the outside.
同时宇航员们可以腾出他们的手来在外面工作
So it can be used in several ways.
所以 它可以在好几个方面上使用
ERA has been specially designed for collaboration between man and machine.
ERA是专门为人与机器之间的协作而设计的
The astronauts can even operate the arm from outside the Space Station during spacewalks
宇航员甚至可以在空间站外进行太空行走时操纵机械臂
using a remote control which has been optimized to be used by astronauts in bulky space suits.
他们会使用一个为穿着笨重太空服的宇航员优化过的遥控装置
French ESA astronaut Thomas Pesquet who is currently at the Space Station
目前在空间站的欧空局法国宇航员托马斯·佩斯凯
will be involved in ERA's commissioning when the arm first arrives at the Space Station.
将参与ERA机械臂首次到达空间站时的调试工作
Later, Mathias Maurer and Samantha Cristoforetti
随后 宇航员马蒂亚斯·毛雷尔和萨曼塔·克里斯托福雷蒂
will take part in the installation and operation of ERA through various spacewalks.
将通过多次太空行走参与ERA的安装和运行工作
One of ERA's first tasks will be to install the radiator and airlock of the NAUKA module
ERA的首要任务之一 将是安装科学号舱段的散热器和气闸舱
so the laboratory can become operational
以便该实验舱能够开始运作
and ERA can use this airlock to move payloads from inside the Station to outside.
ERA可以利用这个气闸舱将有效载荷从空间站内转移到站外
When we operate the ERA on the ISS
当我们在国际空间站上操作ERA的时候
菲利普·肖内扬斯，ERA项目经理，欧空局
We're obviously going to learn a lot about how to use robots in space
我们显然会学到很多关于如何在太空中使用机器人
and how the robots work in space.
以及机器人如何在太空中工作的知识
We'll have feedback to our engineering process
我们将会对我们的工程流程进行反馈
if we finally know, what is the performance during its use in space.
如果我们最终知道 机械臂在太空中使用时的性能是什么样的
We also learn on what we can best do with robots
我们还会学习如何最好的发挥机器人的作用
and what we can best do with people and learn about the cooperation.
和我们如何发挥人的作用 并学习如何合作
And all of that is going to be very, very useful when we would go further into the universe
并且所有这些在我们进一步进入宇宙时都将是非常有用的
and still have for sure robots initially,
当然最初的任务肯定还是只有机器人
but maybe at some point in time also people with robots.
但也许在未来某天 会是人和机器人一起执行任务
We're really looking forward to all what we can learn from the experience on the ISS with ERA.
我们真的很期待我们能从国际空间站上ERA的经验中学到什么
ERA is another example of cooperation between Europe and Russia
ERA是欧洲和俄罗斯之间合作的另一个例子
and a tribute to the excellence of European industry.
并且它也体现了欧洲工业的卓越
The project was commissioned by ESA and largely funded by the Dutch government
该项目由欧空局委托 主要由荷兰政府资助
with Airbus Defence and Space Netherlands as its prime contractor.
空客国防航天荷兰分公司是其主要的承包商
Now the European Robotic Arm will fly to the ISS
现在 欧洲机器臂将飞往国际空间站
and with it a new era dawns for the International Space Station
并且随着它的到来 国际空间站即将开启一个新的时代
already one of humankind's largest achievements.
即使国际空间站已经是人类最大的成就之一
ERA offers a look into the future of space robotics
ERA提供了一个对空间机器人技术的未来
and the cooperation between human and machine as we further explore our universe.
以及在我们进一步探索宇宙时人类和机器之间合作的展望